Guide to the Social Ethics Pamphlet Collection
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Student Papers, Series III
  - O-R
    - Punishment or rehabilitation: a brief study of federal prisons with special reference to the Federal Correctional Institute at Danbury, Connecticut, n.d. (Box 86, Folder 13)
    - Alcoholics Anonymous in New London and Mystic, Connecticut, 1951 (Box 86, Folder 14)
    - A study of the programs of American student Y.W.C.A.'s in the fields of social responsibility and world relatedness, 1950 (Box 86, Folder 15)
    - A study of the Farmers Union and The American Farm Bureau Federation, 1950 (Box 86, Folder 16)
    - Industrial Lawrence, 1942 (Box 87, Folder 1)
    - The reasons for statutory policy changes between 1946 and 1952 in the program of the Division of Public Assistance (Office of the Commissioner of Welfare) the State of Connecticut (Box 87, Folder 2)
    - Racial restrictive covenants in housing: a review of legal aspects, a study of 77 ministers' attitudes and their churches practices in Chicago and St. Louis, 1948 (Box 87, Folder 3)
      Subjects: Law; Race relations
    - The Shoreline Community General Hospital: a dream and a challenge, 1954 (Box 87, Folder 4)
    - re. political leanings of the Negro community in the 1952 presidential election (Box 87, Folder 5)
      Subjects: African Americans; United States--politics and governmet
    - A study of seven organizations contributing to interracial programs in New Haven, n.d. (Box 87, Folder 6)
    - Legal definitions of a "Negro" in the South: an investigation into their nature and purpose, 1964 (Box 87, Folder 7)
      Subjects: Law; Race relations; Southern States
    - United World Federalists, Inc.--February, 1947 to November, 1948, 1949 (Box 87, Folder 8)
      Comment: includes papers and pamphlets issued by the organization
    - The Industrial Parish, 1948 (Box 87, Folder 9)
    - America's forgotten people, 1950 (Box 87, Folder 10)
    - The Russian church and atheism, 1948 (Box 87, Folder 11)
      Subjects: Russian Orthodox Church
  - S
    - Television and the home, 1951 (Box 87, Folder 12)
    - The Church and rural life; Criteria for Judging Agencies of Social Change, 1943,n.d. (Box 87, Folder 13)
    - Negro theological education, 1943 (Box 88, Folder 1)
    - A survey of the First Congregational Church, Old Greenwich, Connecticut, 1947 (Box 88, Folder 2)
      Subjects: Old Greenwich--church history
    - Melting pot of the world, 1952 (Box 88, Folder 3)
    - The Orthodox church in Russia, 1948 (Box 88, Folder 4)
    - The Day law: a study of the Day law which prevents education of the white and Negro races in the same school in the state of Kentucky, and an attempt to stir up sentiment in favor of its repeal, 1947 (Box 88, Folder 5)
    - The National Negro Congress, 1947 (Box 88, Folder 6)
    - An investigation of the Christian Advocate to determine its position on social issues, 1940 (Box 88, Folder 7)
    - Propaganda analysis of two liberal periodicals on U.S. foreign policy in relation to communism and Russia, 1951 (Box 88, Folder 9)
    - Americans For Democratic Action: a general study of its history, basic structure and objectives, 1950 (Box 88, Folder 8)
    - A study: "The Negro in the City of Rochester", 1946 (Box 88, Folder 10)
    - A content analysis of The Christian Sun, 1950 (Box 88, Folder 11)
    - A review of four books on the Southern scene, n.d. (Box 88, Folder 12)
    - A report on two agencies doing work in the field of relief & reconstruction: the American Friends Service Committee, The United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration (Box 88, Folder 13)
    - Water the grass roots: a follow up of the alumni of the Washington Student Citizenship Seminar, 1953 (Box 88, Folder 14)
    - Political significance of Shinto in modern Japan, 1953 (Box 88, Folder 15)
      Subjects: Shinto
    - Christian barbed wire: the Protestant church and the Japanese-American, 1948 (Box 84, Folder 5)
      Subjects: Civil rights; Race relations; Religion and culture; Japanese-Americans
    - Consumer Cooperation in Greenbelt, Md., 1949 (Box 88, Folder 16)
    - A study of the attitudes of New Haven doctors toward euthanasia, 1950 (Box 88, Folder 17)
    - A History of Yale Employee's Union, Local 142, UCW, UMWA, AFL, along with a special reference to Divinity School Dining Hall, 1946 (Box 96, Folder 14)
      Subjects: Labor movement; Yale University
      Comment: contains papers issued by the union and the university
    - A study of funeral practices in New Haven, 1948 (Box 89, Folder 1)
    - Labor Unions and racial discrimination, 1947 (Box 89, Folder 2)
    - A study of the International Council of Community Churches, 1953 (Box 89, Folder 3)
      Subjects: Community churches; Religion and culture
    - Bibliography on the study of the life and mission of the church, 1959 (Box 89, Folder 4)
    - Checkbook justice, 1969 (Box 89, Folder 5)
      Subjects: Law
      Comment: the topic of this paper is the bail bond system
    - Pastoral care of absentee congregations, 1943 (Box 89, Folder 6)
    - Jewish-gentile relations in Sullivan County, New York, 1948 (Box 89, Folder 7)
    - Mississippi Baptist ministers and the Negro (Box 89, Folder 7a)
      Subjects: Baptists; Race relations
    - The mission and the union: two approaches to the indigent alcoholic, 1966 (Box 89, Folder 8)
    - Economic pressures and academic freedom: a study of the Texas Controversy, 1951 (Box 89, Folder 9)
    - Southern Students at Yale Divinity School: a study of the viewpoints of B.D. students from the South/Southwest with attention to the current racial crisis, 1964 (Box 89, Folder 10)
      Subjects: Race relations; Yale University
    - A culture in transition: the cultural integration of the Cherokee Indians of Oklahoma, 1953 (Box 89, Folder 11)
    - Toward an official social action agency within the Methodist Church, 1952 (Box 89, Folder 12)
      Subjects: Methodists; Religion and culture
    - Towards a sense of vocation at the high school level, 1953 (Box 89, Folder 13)
    - Syngman Rhee, an Asian leader?, 1967 (Box 89, Folder 14)
      Subjects: Korea
    - Book review, 1958 (Box 89, Folder 15)
      Subjects: Bible
      Comment: this is a review of the book "Preface To Bible Study", by Alan Richardson
    - Dimensions of juvenile delinquency in Milford, Connecticut, 1967 (Box 89, Folder 16)
      Subjects: Juvenile delinquency; Milford, Connecticut
    - The attitude of Karl Marx toward religion, n.d. (Box 90, Folder 1)
      Subjects: Marxism
    - The Commission on Marriage and the Home of the Federal Council of Churches of Christ in America and its social aspects concerning marriage, 1950 (Box 90, Folder 2)
    - Churches and migrants, 1951 (Box 90, Folder 3)
      Subjects: Migrant labor; Religion and culture
    - Social influences on Whitneyville youth: fifteen case studies, 1944 (Box 90, Folder 11)
      Subjects: Hamden, Connecticut; Youth
    - Retirement policies of New Haven industries, 1954 (Box 90, Folder 4)
    - A report on the Springside Home of the City of New Haven, 1942 (Box 90, Folder 4a)
      Subjects: New Haven; Poverty
    - A study of the Dunbar community, 1948 (Box 90, Folder 5)
      Subjects: Hamden, Connecticut
    - An approach to the understanding of juvenile delinquency: an experiment in aggressive case work and group work, 1955 (Box 90, Folder 6)
    - An exploration in the social philosophy of a sect (The Jehovah's Witnesses), 1955 (Box 90, Folder 7)
    - Universal military training, 1948 (Box 96, Folder 15)
      Subjects: Armed forces; Draft
    - The Episcopal Church and labor (Box 90, Folder 8)
    - A ministry in the shopping center, 1968 (Box 90, Folder 9)
    - Interreligious comity on the American college campus, 1944 (Box 90, Folder 10)
      Subjects: College students; Church work with students
    - Facing the delinquency problem in New Haven, 1944 (Box 90, Folder 12)
    - A study in comparison of the Family Service Agencies of New Haven, Connecticut, 1950 (Box 90, Folder 13)
      Subjects: Family; New Haven
    - A study of the Cheshire Reformatory for Men, 1943 (Box 90, Folder 14)
    - Personnel policies and their relation to the Christian concept of man, 1952 (Box 90, Folder 15)
    - Displaced persons in the New Haven area, n.d. (Box 90, Folder 16)
      Subjects: New Haven; Refugees
    - A normative survey of pastor patient relations at Grace New Haven Community Hospital, 1953 (Box 90, Folder 17)
      Subjects: Medical care; Religion and culture
    - Schisms and tensions among the Disciples of Christ, 1956 (Box 91, Folder 1)
    - A study of nonviolent resistance, 1961 (Box 91, Folder 2)
  - T-W
    - Critical description of the Japanese New Order, 1942 (Box 91, Folder 3)
      Subjects: Japan
    - Social Analysis of a Japanese Urban Church, 1950 (Box 96, Folder 12)
      Subjects: Mission of the Church--Asia; Missions; Japan
    - Social action and the American Baptist Student Workers, 1951 (Box 91, Folder 4)
      Subjects: Baptists; Church work with students; Religion and culture
    - Church-State relations: ana analysis od the Legislative Committee of the Council for Social Action of the Congregational Christian Churches and The National Catholic Welfare Conference, 1950 (Box 91, Folder 5)
      Subjects: Congregational Christian Churches; Catholic Church; Religion and culture; Religion and politics
    - Community organizations and the Puerto Rican immigrant in the City of New Haven, 1957 (Box 91, Folder 6)
    - A study of the North Rocky Mount Baptists Church trial as based on the court's decision and a searching analysis of some of its implications (Box 91, Folder 7)
      Subjects: North Carolina--church history
    - Questionnaire study of the National Study Conference on the Church and Economic Life, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, Frbuary 18-20, 1947, convened by The Federal Council of Churches of Christ in America (Box 91, Folder 8)
    - The Negro in the public schools of New Haven, 1947 (Box 91, Folder 9)
      Subjects: African Americans; Education; New Haven
    - The National Council Outlook: a study of its relations to National and international affairs, 1953 (Box 91, Folder 10)
    - A platform for democracy, n.d. (Box 91, Folder 11)
      Subjects: United states--politics and government
    - Proportional representation method of voting in Cincinnati, 1952 (Box 91, Folder 12)
    - A radio script on juvenile delinquency, 1946 (Box 91, Folder 13)
    - A historical interpretation of the status of the Negro iron and steel worker, 1945 (Box 91, Folder 13)
    - Race relations and the United Lutheran Church in America, 1951 (Box 91, Folder 14)
      Subjects: Lutherans; Race relations
      Comment: includes Christian education materials issued by the church
    - The interracial policy of the Presbyterian Church in the United States, 1951 (Box 91, Folder 15)
      Subjects: Presbyterians; Race relations
    - Nonviolence in the current civil rights struggle, 1964 (Box 91, Folder 16)
    - The Mexican migrant in Michigan, 1942 (Box 91, Folder 17)
      Subjects: Immigrants; Migrant labor
    - Rep. Clare E. Hoffman: a fascist?, 1944 (Box 91, Folder 17)
    - Untitled, 1945 (Box 91, Folder 18)
    - Is Mao Tze-tung Communist?, 1950 (Box 92, Folder 1)
      Subjects: China; Communism
    - A description and evaluation of the distribution and control of alcoholic beverages in the State of Connecticut, 1950 (Box 92, Folder 2)
      Subjects: Alcoholism; Connecticut-politics and government--1865-1950
      Comment: includes newsclippings and information issued by the state
    - Karl Marx and religion, 1968 (Box 92, Folder 3)
    - The history of the just war theory: with special reference to Thomas Aquinas and Francisco de Vitoria, 1969 (Box 92, Folder 3)
    - The interpretive use of social science data by the Board of Temperance of the Methodist Church, 1949-1956, 1961 (Box 92, Folder 4)
      Subjects: Alcoholism; Religion and culture
    - Communism in Japan, 1948 (Box 92, Folder 5)
      Subjects: Communism; Japan
    - A survey of business propaganda in advertising (Box 92, Folder 6)
    - Socialized medicine, n.d. (Box 92, Folder 6a)
    - A survey on the question of whether or not church members are moving from less to more liturgical churches, 1955 (Box 92, Folder 7)
    - A study toward an evaluation of the New Haven Goodwill Industries, Incorporated, 1954 (Box 92, Folder 8)
      Subjects: New Haven; Poverty; Religion and culture
      Comment: includes pamphlets issued by the organization
    - The reaction of the religious press of America to the emergence of Nazism: a study of five magazines through two years, 1950 (Box 92, Folder 9)
      Subjects: American periodicals; Fascism
    - Cost of living and wage study (Box 92, Folder 10)
    - The Soviet religious offensive, 1961 (Box 93, Folder 1)
      Subjects: International relations; Soviet Union
    - The Chinese Communist movement, 1943 (Box 93, Folder 2)
    - Novels as the source for material dealing with economic and social conditions and the ideology of the worker: a study of twenty industrial novels, 1943 (Box 93, Folder 3)
    - Pearl Buck on race relations, 1943 (Box 93, Folder 4)
    - The Christian Social Relations Program of City Councils of Churches, 1944 (Box 93, Folder 4)
      Comment: includes papers and pamphlets from program members
    - Reviews of six books on the South, 1950 (Box 94, Folder 1)
      Subjects: Southern States
    - The race problem: an analysis of news stories in the Atlanta Constitution and the Boston Post, April 7 through May 7, 1943 (Box 94, Folder 2)
      Subjects: American periodicals; Race relations
      Comment: includes news clippings and a sample issue of Color Line newsletter
    - Analysis of a funeral parlor, 1954 (Box 94, Folder 4)
    - The North Shore Freedom Under God Forum and the community of Winnetka, Illinois (Box 94, Folder 3)
      Subjects: Education; Religion and politics
      Comment: Includes papers and pamphlets from the Freedom Clubs of America
    - A study of the blind in New Haven, Connecticut, 1948 (Box 94, Folder 6)
    - The family in communistic Russia, 1948 (Box 94, Folder 5)
      Subjects: Family; Russia
    - Agricultural migrants: the problems encountered in organizing them, 1947 (Box 94, Folder 9)
    - A survey of the parish of the Union Congregational Church of West Haven, 1948 (Box 94, Folder 7)
      Subjects: Connecticut--church history; Religion and culture; West Haven, Connecticut
    - The American Negro Press, 1945 (Box 94, Folder 10)
      Subjects: African Americans; American periodicals
    - Does the role of the minister alienate him from adolescents, 1954 (Box 94, Folder 8)
    - Washington Gladden, n.d. (Box 94, Folder 11)
    - Industrial chaplaincy, 1950 (Box 94, Folder 12)
      Comment: includes an issue of Industrial Chaplaincy News
    - Some impressions about the New Haven Children's Building, 1943 (Box 94, Folder 13)
      Comment: includes papers from the facility
    - Anti-Semitism in New Haven, 1942 (Box 94, Folder 14)
      Subjects: Antisemitism; New Haven
  - Y-Z
    - Platform for democracy, n.d. (Box 94, Folder 15)
    - A survey of the social outlook of the Fraternity of Free and Accepted Masons, 1951 (Box 94, Folder 16)
      Subjects: Freemasons
    - A study of the First Presbyterian Church (Benedict Memorial), New Haven, Connecticut, 1953 (Box 94, Folder 17)
      Subjects: Connecticut--church history; New Haven; Presbyterians
    - Looking backward--looking a little bit sideways: an investigation into a summer's activity and its effect on the good society, 1949 (Box 95, Folder 1)
    - Methodism's vigilantes: Circuit Riders Inc., 1954 (Box 95, Folder 2)
      Subjects: Conservatism; Methodists
    - The nature and causes of racial prejudice, 1961 (Box 95, Folder 3)
    - A socio-economic study of Trinity Lutheran Church, New Haven, Connecticut, 1951 (Box 95, Folder 4)
      Subjects: Connecticut--church history; New Haven; Lutherans
    - Methodist Student Workers: a survey and study of conditions effecting a specific group of those persons engaged in a professional capacity in the Methodist Student Movement, 1946 (Box 95, Folder 5)
      Subjects: Church work with students; Methodists